<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rui Yin on Rui Yin</title>
    <link>https://raytrox.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rui Yin on Rui Yin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 19:16:49 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://raytrox.github.io/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 19:16:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raytrox.github.io/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://raytrox.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 23:40:25 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raytrox.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;rui-yin&#34;&gt;Rui Yin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PDF resume can be downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://raytrox.github.io/files/resume.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-skills&#34;&gt;Technical Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Languages: Java | Golang | Python | JavaScript | TypeScript | C | C++ | SQL | Ruby | Bash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools: Git | JIRA | Bamboo | Docker | Bitbucket | Nomad | NSQ | Postman | VSCode | IntelliJ | Supervisor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge: RESTful | Computer Networking | Database Design | Machine Learning | OO Design | Distributed Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-experience&#34;&gt;Work Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;software-developer-netapp-inc---co-op--may-2020---current&#34;&gt;Software developer, NetApp Inc. - Co-op | May 2020 - current&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product: StorageGRID&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completed several API/UI improvement stories and fixed bugs for StorageGRID, a Distributed Storage platform support AWS S3 and Swift protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implemented a new feature using Ruby to support secure external Prometheus connection independently with the help of senior developers and presented the feature to the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implemented the UI and the relevant modal for the new feature according to the UI mockup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigated options for adding a read-only mode to the current system, implemented the backend with Ruby and adjusted the frontend accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech stack: Ruby on Rails | AngularJS | HTML | CSS | Python | Bash | Prometheus | Grafana | Angular&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;teaching-assistant-the-university-of-british-columbiasep-2019---dec-2019&#34;&gt;Teaching Assistant, The University of British Columbia｜Sep 2019 - Dec 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instructed students in office hours to aid with assignments, course materials of a 3rd-year course on Operating Systems including debugging assignments and illustrating concepts such as memory hierarchy and file systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invigilated and marked the exams and graded the assignments as directed by instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;software-qa-engineer-vipre-formerly-fusemail---co-op--jan-2019---aug-2019&#34;&gt;Software QA engineer, VIPRE (formerly Fusemail) - Co-op | Jan 2019 - Aug 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product: VIPRE Security&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed a Golang based test automation tool to check result of REST calls. The tool uses docker to bring up all services and check database, NSQ message, HTML response based on the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oversaw the manual, load, automation and performance tests for a LDAP-based new product, created necessary mock services for test automation and presented the demo to stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attended daily scrum meetings and worked on various verification tickets across such as UI or database change in both development and staging environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech stack: Golang | Docker | MySQL | Bash | NSQ | Python | Bamboo | RESTful | Supervisor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;staff-assistant-beijing-bls-spain-visa-centre--jan-2016---may-2016&#34;&gt;Staff Assistant, Beijing BLS Spain Visa Centre ｜ Jan 2016 - May 2016&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checked information for over 50 applicants per day in a team of 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took fingerprints and photos of over 30 applicants per day Individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-checker--html-golang-restful--dec-2019---jan-2020&#34;&gt;Course Checker – HTML, Golang, RESTful | Dec 2019 - Jan 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parsed html and notified the user by sending email once there are seats available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used ReactJS, semantic UI framework to build the frontend and MongoDB to store the monitoring info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dns-resolver--java-dns-udp--oct-2019&#34;&gt;DNS Resolver – Java, DNS, UDP | Oct 2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recursively make the DNS request to the root server to get the IP address for the given domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracted information from DNS responses based on DNS packet compression rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;insight-ubc--typescript-html-css-restful-query-language-design-testing--sep-2018---dec-2018&#34;&gt;Insight UBC – TypeScript, HTML, CSS, RESTful, Query Language Design, Testing | Sep 2018 - Dec 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implemented a RESTful web server using TypeScript as backend and Bootstrap as frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrote a query language interpreter that performs valid query requests for the POST method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implemented a recursive method to achieve the same functionality as Document.getElementById()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disassembler--assembly-language-c-gdb--jul-2018&#34;&gt;Disassembler – Assembly Language, C, GDB | Jul 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build an application in C that translate the binary file to corresponding Assembly code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-shopping-database--oracle-sql-java-jdbc--feb-2018---apr-2018&#34;&gt;Online Shopping Database – Oracle SQL, Java, JDBC | Feb 2018 - Apr 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designed and built a relational database application for an online shopping system to manage stock, financial and customer data using Oracle SQL queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worked with a team of 4 members by planning and delegating tasks to complete the task within the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed a friendly multi-user interface using Java, wrote an automated test and presented to TAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;busesrus-android-app--junit-test-xml-json-parsing-java--mar-2017---apr-2017&#34;&gt;Buses’R’Us Android App – Junit Test, XML, JSON parsing, Java | Mar 2017 - Apr 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed an Android app that maps the location of stops and bus routes on the Vancouver Transit System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used XML parsing and JSON parsing to parse Translink arrival and departure data from the AOI to display information and implemented the Junit test framework to test the functionality of each component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BSc, Computer Science, University of British Columbia (Vancouver, Canada) | Sep 2016 - current (Expected graduation date: May 2021)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cumulative GPA: 4.2/4.33 (average: 88.8%)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major GPA: 4.3/4.33 (average: 89.6%)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;awards&#34;&gt;Awards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trek Excellence Scholarship | 2018, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trek Excellence Scholarships are offered every year to students in the top 5% of their undergraduate year, faculty, and school. Domestic students receive an award of $1,500 and international students receive an award of $4,000. Awards of $1,000 are also given to international students who are in the top 5% to 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faculty of Science International Student Scholarship | 2018, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scholarships of amounts of up to $10,000 each are offered to continuing international students in the Faculty of Science, Vancouver campus. Students selected for these scholarships must have completed at least 30 credits towards their undergraduate degree or be entering the second year of their program. Students must demonstrate strong academic achievement, engagement in the Faculty, and the potential to make a scholarly contribution within their chosen field of study. The scholarships are made on the recommendation of the Faculty of Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dean of Science Scholarship | 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The awards are offered to undergraduate students in science and are made on the recommendation of the Faculty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;languages&#34;&gt;Languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mandarin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-interests&#34;&gt;Personal Interests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video Editing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NBA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>